

Analytic web developer whose focus is on the prototyping, testing, and implementation stages of UX design. Trained to effectively communicate complex institutional knowledge to both experts and nonexperts. Strong self-starter who consistently seeks additional professional development.

P: 774-633-0845

E: wynlnelson@gmail.com

W: wynnelson.com

in: linkedin.com/in/wynnelson

O: github.com/wynnelson

## Experience

Jan 2021 - Current Institute for Transportation Research and Education

**Web Application Developer** 

My holistic approach to working on web applications such as NMCOAST, ArtVal, and Trip Maker provided a revitalizing focus. I designed, developed, and implemented features that exceeded project goals while staying on or ahead of schedule.

Aug 2016 - Dec 2020

North Carolina State University

**Teaching Graduate Student** 

I effectively communicated technical concepts to more than 175 students by instructing four undergraduate courses. During Covid-19 I adaptively developed all course materials for an asynchronous online course.

Jun 2016 – Aug 2016 Jun 2015 – Aug 2015 Cell Signaling Technology

**Research Assistant** 

By developing data visualizations and providing mathematical justification, I created company buy-in for DNA sequence clustering methods.

Education

North Carolina State University

Master of Science in Mathematics

Gordon College

**Bachelor of Science in Mathematics, Minor in Computer Science** 

Skills

Javascript Node.js UX Design HTML CSS API Development

Wireframing React Python Data Analysis Sketch SQL Unix

Certifications

Introduction to Design
Teaching and Communication
Accessibility in the Classroom
Project SAFE Ally

Springboard

NC State Graduate School

NC State IT Accesibility Office

NC State Office for Institutional Equity and Diversity